JACOB ROTH

Richmond, VA

Phone: 540-435-4472 | Email: jakeroth0@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/jakeroth0 | github.com/jakeroth0 | https://rebrand.ly/jakeroth0

Summary

Front End Web Developer with a strong background in media production and video editing. Proven experience in designing and deploying responsive mobile-first applications, utilizing a variety of web technologies. Recognized for attention to detail, creative problem-solving, and a commitment to continuous learning.

Technical Skills

Technical Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Front-end Libraries: React, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Handlebars.js **Back-end Technologies**: Node.js, Express, Sequelize, Mongoose, RESTful API

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, IndexDB

Other Skills: Figma, Agile, Jest, Adobe Suite, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Final Cut Pro X, DaVinci Resolve 17,

Lightroom, Photoshop, Illustrator, Project Management Software

Projects

Tech Pail | github.com/jakeroth0/theTechPail | rebrand.ly/techpail

- Created and deployed a responsive, mobile-first blog site
- Designed UI, utilized MySQL for database, Sequelize as the ORM, and Handlebars.js as the template engine
- Authentication built with Express-Session

MarvelousMoves | rebrand.ly/marvelous-moves

- Developed a site for Marvel fans with character information and related gifs
- Integrated data from Marvel's API and Giphy's API, with a responsive UI using Tailwind CSS

Employee Management System | rebrand.ly/EmployeeManagement

- Built a CLI app for CRUD operations on a MySQL database
- Used Node.js and Inquirer for app development

Experience

Full Stack Developer, University of Richmond Coding Bootcamp

2022 - Present | Richmond, VA

Developed and deployed web applications, working with a variety of web technologies and frameworks.

Video Specialist, Hope Church EPC

2020 - Present | Richmond, VA

Responsible for web design and development, video creation, and content curation.

Completed over 400 video projects, from concept to delivery.

Owner & Executive Producer, Jake Roth Media Production

2017 - Present | Richmond, VA

Directed and managed over 90 projects, raising over \$400,000 for clients.

Certified Part 107 license holder for drone operation.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp Certificate: University of Richmond, Richmond, VA A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS. **BA, Major in Public Relations and Cinema:** Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, VA